Wesly Marpaung IT Staff

Jakarta, Indonesia 10000 • + (62) 878-72680475 • weslymarpaung 5@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/wesly-marpaung

SUMMARY

A recent college graduate with a degree in Information Systems. Experienced a year apprenticeship in the automotive industry. Result driven and motivated in collecting, organizing, and transforming data using databases tools. Great understanding in Microsoft Office, Enterprise Resource Planning with Odoo, and programming languages such as PHP, HTML, Javascript, and SQL. Provide high value services in business requirements analysis using Business Process Model and Notation (BPMN) and modelling systems with Unified Modelling Language (UML).

EXPERIENCE

PT SINAR KENCANA SEJATI Production Planning Inventory Control Intern

Bantar Gebang, Bekasi FEBRUARY 2023 - AUGUST 2023

- Analyzing the business processes of companies regarding material and product control. Produce a document consisting of BPMN and UML.
- Developing information systems material supply monitoring using the framework CodeIgniter.
- Coordinating with the production manager and related departements regarding the procurement tracking process based on estimated customers demand in Purchase Order to create a Purchase Request letters.
- Doing stock opname activities periodically to make sure the amount of items in the system correspond to the actual number in the warehouse.
- Analyzing data to determine the underlying data differences between the amount of materials for electroplating process in the warehouse and the amount in the system.
- Creating an excel document to process goods out to subcont, so that companies have both finished and unfinished electroplating material. Reduced the time for processing data by 20 minute.

PT WIKA INDUSTRI MANUFAKTUR Research and Development Intern

Cileungsi, Bogor MARCH 2022 - OCTOBER 2022

- Collecting transaction data in the use of Battery Swapping Station (BSS) machines and help exchange the batteries process for electric motor vehicle.
- Manage data on a whole range of problems that occurred during the exchange of batteries like problems with battery swapping station machines, on electric vehicles, and batteries. Communicate with the instructor to find a solution in case of the problem.
- Processing all the data gathered to get information on the most troubled battery exchange location, the most infrequent location of BSS transactions. And select locations that have the opportunity to get high intensity with the use of BSS machines.

EDUCATION

POLITEKNIK STMI JAKARTA Bachelor of Information System GPA: 3.92 / 4.00 Jakarta, Indonesia 2019-2023

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Program Management: SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle), BPMN, Resource Planning, MS Project.
- Technical Skills: Microsoft Office, Python, PHP, HTML, Javascript, ERP with Odoo, CodeIgniter framework.
- Soft Skilss: Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Time Management, Effective Communication, Teamwork.
- Certifications: BNSP Development of Information System Business Process in Manufacturing Industry.